SUMMARY __

My experience spans building small apps and managing large systems, making me a perfect candidate for various-scale problems. My enthusiasm drives me further into the software fundamentals, which helps me gain the required knowledge to maintain the application from writing the code to deployment in production with full test coverage. I am enthusiastic about making a meaningful contribution as a software engineer and aim to provide innovative software solutions.

Experience ___

SOFTWARE ENGINEER STUDENT

09.10.2023-present

WSIB

During my co-op program, I was responsible for both **full-stack software development** and **DevOps** tasks. My responsibilities were:

- Migrated **Jenkins** application to **kuberntes** using the **Jenkins Operator** with **Configuration as a Code** setting. This was done using preconfigured jobs, custom-signed certificates, and Artifactory repository configuration.
- Developed **full-stack** software application using **React** on the front, **Spring framework** and Microsoft SQL (+**liquibase** database management) on the backside to aim at automating the deployment process for different teams in the company. It drastically reduced the time between the development and deployment phases.

JUNIOR/MIDDLE SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT EPAM SYSTEMS

08/2022 - 04/2023

As a software engineer, I worked with an **e-commerce application** that was built using the **ATG** framework. Although this technology is old, the knowledge of container technology facilitates my better understanding of how modern alternatives work, such as the Spring framework. A crucial part of my participation was to ensure **product deliverability** throughout the whole time. My tasks included:

- Developed new API calls by introducing a security layer, which allowed clients to work with an application more **secure**.
- Participated in **Sprint** planning and estimating user stories using **Jira/Confluence** tool, aiding in setting realistic task time frames.
- Designing **SQL** scripts for **OracleDB** to update the application schemas.
- Engaged in **Code Review** sessions to analyze and provide feedback on colleagues' code, enhancing code quality.
- Designed comprehensive **unit** tests that contributed to achieving **100% code** coverage and improving code reliability.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO, MASTERS DEGREE

09/2023 - 09/2024

MME Department

- Completed the course on gaining proficiency in **software testing and quality assurance techniques**, including coverage criteria evaluation, **symbolic execution**, constraint solving with SMT solvers, inductive invariants, **deductive verification**, invariant synthesis, and Software Model Checking. These skills are required to evaluate and improve software quality across various testing scenarios and methodologies.
- Completed the course on identifying real-world examples of security and privacy failures in prevalent technologies and proposing adjustments to enhance user-centric considerations.

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF KYIV-MOHYLA ACADEMY, BACHELOR DEGREE

09/2019 - 06/2023

Applied math

- Completed a Front-end engineering course with Javascript being used on the front/server side to gain a profound understanding of full-stack development. The final project included a website on Pizza delivery with Google GPS service to estimate the delivery time from a given address.
- Completed Spring-boot course provided a deep understanding of Spring configuration, logging and custom modules.

FREIE UNIVERSITY OF BERLIN, EXCHANGE PROGRAM

10/2022 - 03/2023

Informatics

• Completed course on **Haskell**, gaining proficiency in functional programming concepts, such as **lambda functions**, which are widely used today in Java.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

VOLUNTEER4/2022 - 5/2022

You4Ukraine

Developed a **Merch** shop for supporting Ukraine using **Spring Framework**. Although the time was restrictive, our team only collected **2500\$** in 1 month. My tasks involved:

• Implemented **API** for managing items in the shop, allowing front-end applications to communicate with the server.

- Utilized a **mapper** mechanism to convert DB objects into response objects (dto) and vice versa.
- Deployed the application on the AWS EC2 instance and used AWS S3 to store static data, such as images.

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE Java | Kotlin | Python | JS (Node.JS)

FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS Intellij IDEA | Spring(boot, jpa, web) | Mockito

BUILD TOOLS Maven | Gradle | Jenkins | Docker | Kubernetes

MESSAGE BROKERS Kafka | RabbitMQ
AGILE TOOLS Jira | Confluence

DATABASES Oracle DB (Oracle SQL Developer) | MySQL | Mongo DB | PostgreSQL | Microsoft SQL

VCS Git | Gitlab

API TOOLS Postman | Swagger LIBRARIES Junit | React | Selenium

CLOUD PROVIDERS AWS (EC2, S3 etc.) | Google Cloud LANGUAGES Ukrainian C2 | English C1 | German B2